Donald J. Perreault, Sr. Papers VHP2005/1
CCSU Veterans History Project
Donald J. Perreault Sr. Papers
Bulk, 1968-1971
Bulk, 1968-1971 1968 - 1971, 2005
VHP2005/1
CCSU Veterans History Project
133.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
The collection details Donald Perreault’s experiences and impressions during his enlistment in the Vietnam War. A video interview was conducted on January 30, 2006. Materials in the collection also contains digitized copies of personal and military manuscripts, photographs, audio correspondence, and field maps. The records, which date from 1967 thru 1971, provide evidence of American troop combat activity and troop deployment, enemy activity and engagement, and U.S. military moral and courage.
Perreault, Donald J., Sr., (Donald Joseph), 1944 -
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research
Biographical/Historical note
Donald J. Perreault enlisted as Regular Army for a three year enlistment after completion of a master's degree and having received a high draft number. He was accepted for military intelligence training. His basic training was completed at Ft. Dix (New Jersey) followed by Advanced Individual Training (AIT) for 10 weeks at Ft. Holabird (Maryland), Intel School. Upon completion of AIT he was assigned to HQ Company Field Force II, III Corps, G-2 - Plans and Operations near Bien Hoa AB Vietnam. His primary duty was preparation of daily summaries of field operations reports. The field units submitted reports to G-2, which were summarized for use in planning for unit orders. He observed rocket attacks in the area during the 2nd Tet Offensive in 1969, but did not witness any action otherwise. Perreault arrived in Vietnam October 1968 and left in October 1969. Upon completion of his tour of duty he was awarded a Bronze Star for meritorious service. When he returned to United States Perreault was assigned to the North American Air Defense Command (NORAD) in Colorado. At NORAD he maintained an intelligence library. He remained at NORAD until completion of his three (3) years of active duty in 1971.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Technical metadata of each digitial object was extracted and encoded in PREMIS Preservation metadata format.
Preservation Metadata
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Arrangement note
Series I: Presonal Papers
Series II: Military Documents
Series III: Multi-Media
Series IV: Oversized
United States. Army.; United States. Military Assistance Command, Vietnam .; United States. Military Assistance Command, Vietnam. Field Force. (II); Bie^n Ho`a (Vietnam); cartographic materials; Fort Dix (N.J.); Fort Holabird (Md.); Interviews; Long Bi`nh (Ðo^`ng Nai, Vietnam); Manuscript; Photographs; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Military intelligence -- United States; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American
- Series I: Persoanl Papers, VHP2005/1.I
  - Rogers Rangers Standing Orders, Reprint September 1967; VHP2005-1.I.01
  - Certificate of Training, May 29, 1968; VHP2005-1.I.02
  - Donald Perreault's Vietnam War Journal, October 8, 1968 - October 30,1969; VHP2005-1.I.03
  - Transcript of Donald Perreault's Vietnam War Journal, October 8, 1968 - October 30,1969; VHP2005-1.I.04
  - Letter from department of the Army to Mr. Donat Perreault inforing the arrival of Donal Perreault in Vietnam, October 19, 1968; VHP2005-1.I.05; 2.0 Digital files
  - Thanksgiving Menu at Headquaters and Headquarters Company, II Field Force, Vietnam, 1968; VHP2005-1.I.06; 5.0 Digital files
  - Holiday greeting from Donald Perreault to his parents while he was in Vietnam, December 12, 1968; VHP2005-1.I.07; 5.0
  - DA Form 2139, Military Pay Voucher, Clothing, and Equipment, 1969; VHP2005-1.I.08; 5.0 Digital files
  - Form DD-214 Discharge Papers and Veterans Separation Documents, March 1971; VHP2005-1.I.09
  - The Bronze Star Medal, September 25, 1969; VHP2005-1.I.10
- Series II: Military Documents, VHP2005/1.II
  - II Field Force, Vietnam. Operational Report - Lessons Learned, February 1 - April 30, 1969; VHP2005-1.II.1; 5.0
  - Intelligence Report, March 11, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.02; 4.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, March 12, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.03; 11.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, March 13, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.04; 8.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, March 14, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.05; 5.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, June 7, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.06; 12.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, June 8, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.07; 2.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, June 9, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.08; 5.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, June 30, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.09; 5.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, June 30, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.10; 16.0 Digital files
  - Intelligence Report, n.d.; VHP2005/1.II.11; 4.0 Digital files
  - Third Quarterly Review CPP (Combined Campaign Plan), 1969; VHP2005/1.II.12; 24.0 pages
    Note
    This item is part of "Republic of Vietnam and Free World Military Forces 1969 COMBINED CAMPAIGN PLAN" See http://www.counterinsurgency.org/1969%20Campaign%20Plan/1969%20Campaign%20Plan.htm accessed April 2010
  - "Tour 365" a booklet published by U.S. Army given to soldiers after their service in Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.II.13; 66.0 pages
- Series III: Multi-Media, VHP2005/1.III
  - Subseries A: Still Images, VHP2005/1.IIIa
    - Donald Perreault Basic Training, Fort Dix, NJ, May 1968; VHP2005/1.IIIa.01
    - Donal Perreault leaving Bradley Field in Connecticut for Vietnam, October, 2, 1968; VHP2005/1.IIIa.02
    - Headquaters II Filed Force Vietnam, G-2 (Intelligence), 1969; VHP2005/1.IIIa.03
    - Donald Perreault, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.IIIa.04
    - Donald Perreault at work desk, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.IIIa.05
    - Donale Perreault writing home. Picture of his future wife on table. Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.IIIa.06
    - Lockers in Donald Perreault living quater, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.IIIa.07
      General note
      Donald’s locker on left. Roommate—Madison “Skip” Esterly on right
    - Donald Perreault, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.08
    - Donald Perreault and Madison “Skip” Esterly, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.09
    - Donald Perreault sitting on bunk in hooch (Vietnam War era military slang for a thatched hut, barracks), Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.10
    - Donald Perreault, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.11
    - Building #1, Donald Perreault’s barracks, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.12
    - R & R Center, Vung-Tau, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.13
    - Notice of movie cancellation at the "Cinima DD", Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.14
    - Donald Perreault bailing out hooch after monsoon, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.15
    - Phuc the laundry lady, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.16
    - Donald Perreault outside hooch, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.17
    - Latrine at G-2, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.18
    - Swimming pool at G-2, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.19
    - Sergeant Major Cecil on Company St., ammo dump explosion in center background. Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.20
    - Donald Perreault and Madison “Skip” Esterly outside mess hall, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.21
    - Donald Perreault receiving Bronze Star from Brigadier General B. E. Huffman, Jr. and Sergeant Major Cecil, Vietnam, September 25, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.22
    - Donald Perreault wearing bronze star received from Brigadier General B.E. Huffman, Jr. and Sergeant Major Cecil, Vietnam, September 25, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.23
    - G-2 Headquarters II Field Force list of short timers, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.24
      Dark names are leaving service after their tour of duty, light names have more time to serve after leaving Vietnam. Donald Perreault's name is sixth from the top of the list. Left Column = State from, Middle column = name, Right column = ETS (expiration of term of service) or PCS (permanent change of station). Vietnam
    - Donald Perreault’s “Freedom Bird” (a nickname for government contract flight that bring soldiers back to the United State after tour of duty) at airfield, Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.25
    - Replacement troops arriving. Tail of Donald Perreault’s “freedom bird” can be seen on the right. Vietnam, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.26
    - Ent Air Force Base with Pike’s Peak in the background. Colorado Springs, CO, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.27
    - Army Air Defense Command building (ARADCOM), Donald Perreault’s work assignment after Vietnam. Colorado Springs, CO, 1969; VHP2005/1.III.28
    - Donald Perreault at Peterson Field, 1970; VHP2005/1.III.29
    - Donald Perreault at VHP dedication, CCSU New Britain, CT, November 21, 2005; VHP2005/1.III.30
  - Subseries B: Moving Images, VHP2005/1.IIIb
    - Oral History Interview with Donald J. Perreault Sr., January 21, 2001; VHP2005/1.IIIb.1; 2.0 dvd; Hurst, Eileen (Disk VHP2005/1 Interview DVD)
      Interviewer: Eileen Hurst
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video
- Series IV: Oversized, VHP2005/1.IV (Map-case OV Roll 1)
  - Map of Bien Hoa-Long Binh-Long Thani Military Complex Vietnam, 1:50,00. Stock number L701463301 (sheet number 63301, series L7014). Map identifies ground vegetation, airfields, roads, route markers, bridges, railroads, villages, canals and ditches, Churches, Temples, post offices, cemeteries’, dams, lakes and ponds, and differing types of terrain. Aerial photography was used to identify the vegetation. Among other designations the map includes boundaries, longitude and latitude coordinates, an elevation guide, and a glossary., 1969; VHP2005/1.IV.01; 2 ft x 2 ft 4 ½ inches
  - Map of War Zones C without accompanying map Key., 1969; VHP2005/1.IV.02; 2 ft x 2 ft 4 ½ inches
  - Map of War Zone D without accompanying map key, 1969; VHP2005/1.IV.03; 2 ft x 2 ft 4 ½ inches